<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Archive xmlns="http://www.qsardb.org/QDB">
    <Name>Prediction of rodent carcinogenicity of aromatic amines: a quantitative structure–activity relationships model</Name>
    <Description>The aromatic amines are widely used industrial chemicals
and can be found in tobacco smoke as well as in products
generated during cooking. In a previous study, we
established quantitative structure–activity relationship
(QSAR) models linking the carcinogenic potency of non-
heterocyclic carcinogenic aromatic amines to a series of
molecular determinants. We also found that QSAR models
for carcinogenic potency were inadequate in describing
the difference between carcinogenic and non-carcinogenic
amines [Benigni,R., Giuliani,A., Franke,R. and Gruska,A.
(2000) Chem. Rev., 100, 3697–3714]. In this paper, we
derived specific QSAR models for separating active from
inactive amines. It appeared that hydrophobicity (as
measured by the octanol/water partition coefficient, logP)
played a major role in modulating the potency of the
carcinogens, whereas mainly electronic (reactivity) and
steric characteristics separated the carcinogens from the
non-carcinogens. Interestingly, a similar pattern was
previously demonstrated by us regarding their mutagenic
activity [Benigni,R., Passerini,L., Gallo,G., Giorgi,F. and
Cotta-Ramusino,M. (1998) Environ. Mol. Mutagen., 32,
75–83]. Based on the QSAR models found, the molecular
determinants of the mechanisms of action of aromatic
amines are discussed in detail. The QSAR models obtained
can be used directly for estimating the carcinogenicity of
other non-heterocyclic aromatic amines for which experi-
mental data are not available. With the QSARs in Benigni
et al. (2000) and the present results, a two-step prediction
of carcinogenicity of aromatic amines is possible: (i) step 1,
yes/no activity from the discriminant functions; and (ii) step
2, if the answer from step 1 is yes then prediction of the
degree of potency from the equations in Benigni et al.
(2000). Thus, QSAR models can contribute to the following:
the direct synthesis of safer chemicals; the estimation of
the risk posed by amines present in the environment;
setting priorities for further experimentation, thus also
reducing the use of experimental animals. Whereas the
quality of in vivo experimental data is often questioned,
the robustness and intepretability of the present results
strongly support the reliability of the rodent carcino-
genicity assay.</Description>
</Archive>
